AMEYA R SHETYE

© (917)-324-2450 | shetye.ameya.7@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/shetyeameyasmu APPLICATION DEVELOPER.

Summary:

A Motivated Engineer with a master's degree and 4 years of relevant Frontend Development, emphasis in Web-based applications and mobile application development; Expertise jQuery, JavaScript, TypeScript, JSON, CSS/CSS3, Swift, Objective C, React hooks, web sockets, Ajax, RESTFUL services, SOAP web services, Node.js. Experience in all phase of Software Development Life Cycle like Requirement Analysis, Implementation and Maintenance, and extensive experience with Agile and SCRUM. Hands on experience in React.js for creating interactive UI's using Oneway data flow, JSX, React Native concepts and state management such as Redux and Context. Strong problem-solving, organizing, communication and planning skills, with ability to work in team environment.

Technical Skills:

100111110111 2111111111	
Environments	Windows, Linux, Mac.
Languages	C, C++, Java, Objective C, Swift, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, HTML, node.js.
Libraries	React, Ajax, jQuery.
Frameworks	AVFoundation, CoreData, SDK, Unity, CoreFoundation, CoreGraphics, Core Animation CoreLocation, CorePDF, CoreVideo, EventKit, iWebKit, Bluetooth(Bluetooth low energy), IOT Camera, SpriteKit, Maps, cocopods, CocoaTouch, KnockoutJs.
Servers	Parse, Heroku, Mongodb, Amazon web services, Firebase.
Development Tools	Visual Studio 2012, visual studio code, Xcode, Android Studio, Postman, GraphQL(Visual Studio Code), Xming, Quartus II, Putty, Cisco Packet Tracer, MATLAB, sketch 3.
Management Tools	Git, SourceTree, BitBucket.
Design patterns	MVC, MVVM, Protocol Oriented Programming, OOP, Singleton.
Unit Testing	Karma, Appium, Selenium.
Browsers	IE, Firefox, Opera, Chrome, Safari, Edge.
Domains	Finance, Social Networking, E-commerce, Mobile Application Development.

Work History:

RumbleOn

Jan 2018- April 2020

Working on the PumbleOn consumer application TeamPumbleon application and Pumbleon Classifieds and Dealer Portal

- Working on the RumbleOn consumer application, TeamRumbleon application and Rumbleon Classifieds and Dealer Portal.
- Objective C was the major language used, worked on converting the current code in objective C to Swift, Enhancements for carplay and iOS watch and maintain code quality and debugging for any errors.
- Creating UI views programmatically and Xib's using autolayout to fit different screen sizes.
- Used Stripe to integrate payment methods.
- Used OCR for Vin decode by clicking a picture of the vin on the bike to decode for make and models.
- Used Nada services for decoding Makes and models.
- Involved in the creation of interface to manage user menu and Bulk update of Attributes using React.JS.
- Work closely with the marketing team to provide the changes required to make the app more user friendly.
- Continuously create updates for the application and update (ship) them on the apple store.
- Elastic Search for scrolling through the inventory.
- Worked on the team app for the appraisal by making it easy for the team to work more efficiently and creating more appraisals for the users to view.
- Rumbleon Classifieds the entire code was react based. Used JavaScript and TypeScript. Worked on grapgql for data queries.

- Used **Redux Thunks** (middleware) to write action creators for Rumbleon Code while for Classifieds we used Context as state management.
- Worked with package managers NPM and Yarn
- Involved to implement various screens for the front end using React.js and used various predefined components from NPM and redux libraries.
- Involved in handling events with React elements, by using the events such as addEventListener.
- Refactored structure of React components and **Redux** containers, to resolve a production performance issue.
- Built **reusable** and **customizable components** for the new website using React.js and typescript to be **responsive** desktop, mobile and tablets.
- Created a chat within classifieds with Progress/kendo library so that the user could contact the other user and get information for his vehicle.
- Worked as a **Project Manager** for the Classifieds project. Responsibilities included but not limited to maintain Jira, creating new tickets gathering required information from business and forwarding them in technical terms to the development team.
- Coordinated with 24 developers offshore from India and SriLanka. Gave them the necessary roles and planed sprints till the launch.
- Code review and buddy testing before moving the code to QA for testing.
- Machine Learning: The code compares the vehicles viewed by the user and provide a closer match for the user from the list of similar makes and models of vehicles available matching the choice and price and make the process automated.
- •Strong experience in writing and updating the technical documents on daily basis with the changes made to the existing environment on daily basis.

Webspun LLC Jan 2017-Nov2017

- Working on a new Stock Exchange application. It helps the user to check his spending's on stocks and helps him to maintain his account while keeping him informed about the market data.
- Swiftis the major language used, a bridging header is created between objective C and swift for the vahoo finance API.
- Working with several internal modules for separate features and 3rd party libraries using cocoa pods.
- Created an authentication page for an application as a prototype using Google Firebase. Features: Navigation Controlled, session management and threading.
- The user can follow the stocks he likes and keep getting the updates through push notifications using DNS server.
- The data is stored using Parse open source DB.
- Yahoo Finance API is used for machine learning.
- Maintain and debugging for any errors. An example, the bug that showed the user number of stocks, which were not necessarily of the same value. Improved the user needs by finding the right match based on user likes and fluctuating market value of the followed stocks.
- Entire dashboard was created for the user in tabular form included with graphs that depicted his spending's.
- Built the entire application from scratch. Using autolayouts and advanced features in swift 3.0 and worked on performance tuning.
- Consumed the Web-services for validating the data from back-end services.
- Working on the carplay and iOS watch.
- Created adhoc builds and released for internal testing.
- Created developer distribution certificates and provisioning files
- Machine Learning: The code compares the user stocks and finds the relative stocks, which have a similar profile.

Research Assistant at SMU

July 2016 – Jan 2017

- Worked in a team developing a wireless network discovery and audit application, which can be used to view the devices, connected to your network.
- It has everything you need to analyze connection problems and find any computer connected to your network that should not be there.
- The language used for the project was swift.
- It provides services such as Ping, Traceroute and WoL (Wakeon LAN), among many others.
- $\bullet \ \, \text{The prototype of mobile learning application story board that I worked on: The main module menu of the application. User may click on any preferable choices. } \\$

- The storyboard design used auto layout.
- The components module needed to make simple network connection before user can do basic configuration on router and switch. When user clicks each component there will be explanation for each component. Designing the explaining code was my task
- Modifying the application icons and splash screens.
- The tutorial module that provides step-by-step process on how to do basic configurations on router and switch. All basic configuration commands will be shown here so user can easily learn how to implement them.
- Jira was used for the testing purpose.
- Generating .ipa files and maintaining Apple Developer Certificates.
- Write clean and concise code which is stable and extensible and unit-tested appropriately.

Axis Electrical PVT LTD. (Intern)

May2013-Jul2014

- Design: In an <u>agile environment</u> worked on security lightning module, taking into consideration the physical and geographical constraints developed a system that could determine the damage that could be caused in terms of life, heritage and surroundings if struck by lightning.
- Collaborated successfully with cross-functional development teams to design and manufacture new products.
- Wrotethecodeforcalculatingthedamagethatwouldbecausedduetothe lightning. The code was written in objective C.
- Collaborated with UI and UX team to make application user friendly by designing the icons used in the application.
- Contributed to the design and development of mobile software libraries using Maxima and KDE frameworks.
- Created efficient and fast front-ends for our consumer site, partner portals, and monetization system and maximized the speed by 15%.
- Production and Marketing- Dealt with Product Management and coordinated with international teams to promote the products and carry out the orders in organized manner and helping the marketing team with the technical aspects. Did a few presentations on the application and explained its workability.

Academic Projects: (Southern Methodist University:- Degree- MSEE)

Aug 2014-May 2016

- **PROJECT** ~ **CALO-METER:** Using Version control Systems (git) for configuration Management, created an application that would allow the user to click a picture of a receipt or bill from a restaurant (PIZZA HUT, STARBUCKS, CHICK FIL A) to find the amount of calories. It runs the database in the application and display the amount of calories for the item/items purchased by just accessing the items mentioned in the bill. Used an OCR that is Tesseract, with the help of SQLite to check the database. Used Coredata and AVFoundation. Language used for the project was Objective C.
- **CHAT APP:** Developed a simple user chat application where the user can connect with his friends using the same application through Bluetooth. Language used was objective C.
- FOLLOWER: This application helps the user remember the people it is following and the people that are following the user. Created a database using Parse and Heroku. The user can follow or un-follow any user. It was similar to the Instagram following mechanism. Language used was Swift.
- WEATHER APP: Using the table View, datasource and delegate created an open weather API which would continuously be updating itself in the background to receive current updates. Used Alamofire to download data from API.
- **DICE GAME:** Built a simple guessing game in which the user has to correctly predict the number on the dice. The user can bet 5 or 10\$ also he has to choose if the number will be an odd or an even number. Alerts have been used to keep the game more interactive and fun. Used Coredata, CoreAudio. Language usedSwift.

Education:

Master of Science: Electrical Engineering.

Southern Methodist University

Dallas, Texas May 2016

Bachelor of Science: Electronics Engineering

Mumbai, India June 2013

University of Mumbai

Certifications

- IDEMI (Institute for Design of Electrical Measuring Instrument) Embedded Systems.
- CCNA- Routing and switching trained.